PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
In Pixar BOX
In Pixar BOX
The method of drawing progresywngo works, but ...
连续动画法虽然不错 但是
it is often difficult to determine where we are going.
它却无法准确把握时间和位置
So let's start with the so-called. key positions.
这时候 “关键张”是个不错的办法
For reflecting the ball to the highest point and the contact with the ground.
对于弹跳球来说 关键张就是最高点和触地点
I'll start from the first frame, high.
我先把最高点当作第一帧
Now cage 9. - a ball on the ground.
然后第九帧是球与地面接触的画面
With these items, I Draw the intermediate frames.
我就能以这两张为依据 加中间张了
The cage 5 is in the middle.
把第五帧画在中间
We call it breaking ( breakdown ).
我们把这种叫做“小原画”
Dorysowuję cage, dividing the space.
继续添加帧 细分其他空间
Chart helps catch in numbers of frames.
这种小标尺能辅助我们追踪这些数字
Excellently! Wskanujmy drawings and odtwórzmy them.
好了 现在可以扫描了
Reproducing the same drawings back, we will show falling ball.
球返回时可以偷个懒 就用刚才这几帧倒放
You can see movement, but hardly realistic.
球弹起来了 不过显得不太真实
It should first make a video auxiliary
在开始画之前 我们可以先实拍段小视频
for an idea of ​​what we're doing.
它能为你提供所需的参考
Remember, coming off the ball faster.
记住 球落下的时候是在不断加速的
5. The cage is in the middle of the animation in terms of time,
我们的第五帧是时间的中间点 也是空间的中间点
but the shot should not then be in the middle of the road.
但其实时间过去一半时 球只走了一少半的距离
I'll draw the cage 5. differently, with the ball closer to the first position.
重新画一下第五帧 让球更靠近最高点
Let it be a 1/3 of the way down.
就画在三分之一的位置吧
Animators have the visual system: time chart shows,
动画师们发明了时间标尺 来直观展现两个关键张之间
how to distribute the frames between key positions.
小原画的空间幅度
5. Thus the frame is 1/3 way between position 1 and 9.
所以记住 1与9中间的第5帧 是在三分之一的位置
Cage 3. Draw 1/3 way between 1 and 5, and so on.
1和5之间的第3帧 是在它们中间三分之一的位置 以此类推
Chart helps to deploy during the intermediate frames.
标尺能帮我们把控小原画的空间幅度 正确的节奏
Recreate - and ball speeds, falling.
回放一下 现在球是加速冲向地面的
Let us now see how to apply the method with key positions in the computer.
现在来看看 怎样在电脑上用“关键张”来做动画
We will start as before from the cage first with the ball in the air.
和刚才一样 我们把球放在最高点 当作第一帧
We jump to the cage 9, with the ball on the ground.
然后直接到第九帧 把球拉到画面下方接触地面
The computer shows us this graph.
电脑出现这样一个图形
Is a timing diagram;
看上去跟二维时间标尺很像
We see how they are calculated intermediate frames.
而且电脑会自动计算出其他中间帧的位置
On the horizontal axis is the time
水平坐标代表的是时间
and on the vertical - the height at which the ball.
垂直坐标则代表球的高度
Projecting the situation of each frame on a vertical axis,
如果把每个交点都投射到y轴上
We get the timing diagram as in animation done by hand.
则跟二维动画师用的时间标尺一摸一样
The computer automatically connects positions of straight lines.
电脑会默认用直线连接两个关键帧
We call it linear interpolation.
我们叫它“线性插值”
The result is a uniform distribution of positions.
这样默认形成的空间分配是均匀的
The reconstitution ball moves at a constant speed.
我们播放一下能看出 球是匀速运动的
Now you try.
现在轮到你了
Make a convincing animation using linear interpolation.
看看你能不能用线性插值来做一段以假乱真的弹跳动画
Hint that you can add intermediate frames, where you want.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
小提示：你可以用添加关键帧的方式来调整空间和节奏哦  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox